<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <author email="marcelschoen@users.sourceforge.net">Marcel Schoen</author>
    <title>Bookmarks</title>
  </properties>
  <meta name="keyword" content="java, maven, build"/>
<body>

<section name="Bookmarks">
	
	<subsection name="Overview">
	<p><p></p>
	PDFDoclet allows to create a bookmark outline which makes it easier to access
	the various parts of the document. The default bookmark outline structure for
	an API for which an overview and appendices were specified is this:
	</p>
	<pre>
        + Title Page
        + Overview
        + All Classes
        + Packages
        + Appendices
        + Index
	</pre>
	<p><p></p>
	Within each package entry, the structure always looks like this:
	</p>
	<pre>
        + Package name
          + Class name
            + Fields
            + Constructors
            + Methods
	</pre>
	<p><p></p>
	It is possible, however, to change the bookmark structure in various ways, as
	explained in the following sections.
	</p>
	</subsection>
	
	<subsection name="Bookmark Labels">
	<p><p></p>
	The following list shows the configuration properties which can be used to
	override the default bookmark labels.
	<pre>
        label.bookmarks.title=My Title
        label.bookmarks.index=My Index
        label.bookmarks.overview=My Overview
        label.bookmarks.packages=The Packages
        label.bookmarks.otherPackages=Remaining Packages
	</pre>
	The last two properties are mutual exclusive. The last one ("<code>..otherPackages</code>") 
	is used only in conjunction with the <code>-group</code> parameter (see next section).
	</p>
	</subsection>
	
	<subsection name="Bookmark Grouping">
	<p><p></p>
	PDFDoclet supports the <code>-group</code> parameter which allows to group certain
	packages together. See Sun's javadoc for a detailled explanation of this parameter.
	</p>
	<p><p></p>
	The packages not included in any of the groups are all under a bookmark with the
	default label "Other Packages". To override this label, set this property:
	<pre>
        label.bookmarks.otherPackages=Remaining Packages
	</pre>
	</p>
	</subsection>
	
	<subsection name="Custom Bookmarks">
	<p><p></p>
	As the example <a href="http://prdownloads.sourceforge.net/pdfdoclet/examples1.pdf?download">example1.pdf</a> 
	shows, it is possible to create custom entries in
	the bookmark outline. This can be achieved with a special kind of HTML anchor
	in the <code>overview.html</code> or a <code>package.html</code>:
	<pre>
        &lt;a name="pdfbookmark" label="Text Label"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	</pre>
	Due to some mysterious behaviour of the HTML parser, it's better to create a 
	separate opening and closing tag, as shown in this example. Usually it also works
	if the HTML tag is closed directly, XML-style, but in certain situations, following
	HTML tags may be turned into links (although they shouldn't). This may be fixed in
	a future release. For the time being, it is recommended to use this notation.
	</p>
	</subsection>
	
</section>

</body>
</document>
